Jericho Mata

San Jose, CA | 201.423.2256 | jericho.mata9@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

3+ years of technical experience with successful Full-Stack deployments and coursework using React, C/C++, and Python. Innovative, passionate, analytical, and looking to hone my skills in software development as well as grow within a company whose values I align with. Driven to collaborate and to learn more about product development.

COURSES & TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Courses: OOP, Algorithm Design, Data Structures, Databases, Machine Learning/ Al, Operating Systems
- Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, C/C++, C#, SQL, JSON, MATLAB, RUST, Haskell
- Libraries/ Frameworks: React, Node.js, Express, Git, Firebase, Flask, Django, Heroku, NumPy, Pandas

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

BudgetBetter | HackCWRU 2022: FinTech Track, 1st Place

DevPost | Live | Github

Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

Python, Flask, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Node, Docker, Heroku

- Money management platform where users input transactions, set goals, and view graphical budgeting trends
- Implemented **Plaid's API** calls to retrieve banking data from over 2000 institutions then categorized transactions into 4 dynamic webpages using **JavaScript** and deployed on **Heroku**
- Integrated **React** and **Flask** to store transactional data for each user into dedicated database to improve **UI** and to increase page load speeds by **15**%
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to authenticate users when retrieving API data to protect users' transactions history

Music Genre Prediction and Web Application

<u>Demo</u> Github

Python, Flask, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, KNN, SVM

Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

- Big data models connected to web application that identifies non-overlapping music genre for classification
- Successfully created **Neural Network** and **Multi-Layer Perceptron** model using **Python** that yielded 86% accuracy in determining correct music genre
- Led web application team of 3 to build frontend using **React** and backend using **Flask** that receives audio files, extracts features, runs model, and sends prediction

Vestibular Migraine Evaluation Tool

Github

Python, Deep Learning, NLP

Jul 2022 - Sep 2022

- A.I. approach to help doctors evaluate patient diagnosis severity using data from social media platforms
- Scraped and extracted over **120,000** Twitter tweets with Vestibular Migraine symptoms using **Python**
- Managed team of 3 developers to extract relevant data from Twitter using natural language processing, resulting in increased accuracy of patient diagnosis by 11%

EXPERIENCE

Freestand | Remote | Full-Stack Web Developer Intern

May 2021 - Sep 2021

- Integrated Cloud Firebase storage, allowing users to directly upload up to 20 .jpg, .png, or.mp4 files to their
 own profile pages and drag files into respective subsections which improved UI/UX
- Designed & implemented full stack CRUD web application to teach financial literacy using React and Node.js

Green Science Games | Davis, CA | *Game Developer Intern*

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

- Created 2D game based on Plants vs. Zombies using **Unity** and **C#** which supported learning of K-6 students'
- Automated customer reporting system in handling issues related to live-image captures and dynamic image renders by developing internal ticketing **query** system within game interface

Finesse Apparel | Sacramento, CA | Website Designer (UI/ UX)

Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

- Created brand and took on multiple roles including logo design using Adobe Illustrator, development of
 website, and delivered content across social media platforms increasing web traffic and sales by 33%
- Oversaw team of 4 developers, acting as project manager for platform transition and developed concepts, target audience, requirements, deadlines, and budgets

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis